This dictionary contains 10957738 lines

It is updated for the spelling reform of 2009
Obsolete spellings have been removed
This dictionary contains verb forms with clitics
Abbrevations and acronyms have been removed and listed in a separate dictionary

According to the LGPLLR license, you can obtain the text version of
this dictionary at http://infolingu.univ-mlv.fr

Contact: unitex@univ-mlv.fr
