#
#     Alexis Neme , alexis.neme@gmail.com
#     March  2013

The 'Fishing-Earthquakes-Water.snt' corpus distributed with Unitex is part of the evaluation test set for modelling the broken plural (cf. Neme, Laporte, 2013). To access the annotated corpus, open Fishing-Earthquakes-Water.snt in the Unitex/Arabic/Corpus folder with the Text > Open menu. It has been preprocessed by Unitex with the PRIM dictionary of broken plurals (Neme, Laporte, 2013) and Neme's (2011) dictionary of verbs.

The unannotated corpus is Fishing-Earthquakes-Water.txt in the same folder. These documents are fully diacritized. Undiacritized versions are provided too.

The text is a small sample of the NEMLAR Arabic Written Corpus (Attia et al., 2005). This corpus was produced and annotated by RDI, Egypt, for the Nemlar Consortium.   It consists of about 500 thousand words of Arabic text from 13 different genres. Each text is provided in 4 different versions: raw text, fully diacritized text, text with Arabic lexical analysis, and text with Arabic POS-tags.

We selected three documents totalling 3 550 tokens (about 10 pages) and containing scientific popularization about three topics: pollution and fishing in Egypt, earthquakes in the world, and quality of water. 

During the construction of our lexicon of BPs, we did not use any part of the corpus: our sources of information were handbooks, reference dictionaries and native speaker competence. Thus, the evaluation tool is independent from the evaluated resource. 

The 267 broken plurals can be obtained and listed in a concordance. 
(cf. Unitex 3.0 or 3.1beta, User Manual, page 79)
- With Unitex, open the preprocessed corpus Unitex/Arabic/Corpus/Fishing-Earthquakes-Water.snt.   
- In order to search for an expression, first open a text . Then click on "Locate Pattern..." in the "Text" menu. 
- Make the following in "Locate pattern in the form of" :
  - select "regular expression:" and input the "<N:q>" in the text box  
 -  choose "index all uterances in text"  
 -  choose "Search algorithm - automaton intersection (higher precision)"
 -  click on "Search" to launch the command.

The number of matches should be displayed (267 matches). Click OK.

A concordance form is displayed, in order to input some concordance parameters. For a better display of Arabic script, select  "Use a Web browser".  
  
Bibliography

Attia, M.; Yaseen, M.; Choukri, K. (2005). Specifications of the Arabic Written Corpus produced within the NEMLAR project, www.NEMLAR.org.
Neme, Alexis; Laporte, Éric (2013). Pattern-and-root inflectional morphology: the Arabic broken plural. Language Sciences 40, 221-250.
Neme, Alexis (2011). A lexicon of Arabic verbs constructed on the basis of Semitic taxonomy and using finite-state transducers. In Proceedings of the International Workshop on Lexical Resources (WoLeR) at ESSLLI.

