This dictionary is an extract of the Serbian morphological
electronic dictionary developed by
Cvetana Krstev and Dusko Vitas form The Belgrade University.

This extract contains about 9510 Delaf entries, that is approximately 
0.7% of the original dictionary. It covers the lexica of the Serbian translation of 
Voltair's "Candide" which is also supplied with this distribution, 
so it is possible to work with this text. In this distribution are also the first 
three chapters of this text full lemmatized and disambiguated.

For the full version of the lexicon, please contact:

Cvetana Krstev
Faculty of Philology
Universty of Belgrade
Studentski trg 3
11000 Belgrade
Serbia
e-mail:cvetana@matf.bg.ac.yu
http://www.matf.bg.ac.yu/~cvetana

or

Dusko Vitas
Faculty of Mathematics
Universty of Belgrade
Studentski trg 16
11000 Belgrade
Serbia
e-mail:vitas@matf.bg.ac.yu
http://www.matf.bg.ac.yu/~vitas

More details about this lexicon are given in the text ReadMe.doc

